<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>General on</title><link>/blazor-webassembly-boilerplate/general/</link><description>Recent content in General on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 11:40:05 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blazor-webassembly-boilerplate/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Overview</title><link>/blazor-webassembly-boilerplate/general/overview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 11:40:05 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blazor-webassembly-boilerplate/general/overview/</guid><description>Blazor WebAssembly Boilerplate # Built with .NET 6.0 and the goodness of MudBlazor Component Library. Incorporates the most essential Packages your projects will ever need. Follows Clean Architecture Principles.
Goals # The goal of this repository is to help developers / companies kickstart their Web Application Development with a pre-built Blazor WebAssembly Boilerplate that includes several much needed components and features.
Note that this is a frontend / client application only!</description></item><item><title>Development Environment</title><link>/blazor-webassembly-boilerplate/general/development-environment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:59:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blazor-webassembly-boilerplate/general/development-environment/</guid><description>fullstackhero&amp;rsquo;s Blazor WebAssembly Boilerplate Project Development needs you to have the following applications / tools available on your machine. Please Note that this project is being built on a Windows 10 Machine using Visual Studio Code IDE.
.NET SDK # As mentioned earlier, this project is built with the latest available .NET SDK, which is .NET 6.0.
Ensure that you have the latest version of the SDK available - Download from Microsoft</description></item><item><title>Getting Started 🚀</title><link>/blazor-webassembly-boilerplate/general/getting-started/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 11:40:05 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blazor-webassembly-boilerplate/general/getting-started/</guid><description>Firstly, make sure that you have already setup your development environment that runs the prerequisite tools and SDKs. Refer Development Environment for details.
To get started with this Boilerplate, here are the avaiable options.
Fork the Repository. Use this if you want to always keep your version of the Boilerplate up-to date with the latest changes. Install using dotnet new . Use this for release versions of the Boilerplate only.</description></item></channel></rss>